Q1)
All the three , the sign bit, exponent and fraction are used to represent a floating point number but precision is the smallest change that 
can be acheived in the floating point number system. In the floating point representation, the 'fractional' part of the number encoding decides the precision
of the number. Higher the number of bits allocated for the fractional part, higher would be the precision. Hence flipping the LSB would give 
us the smallest change. Sign and the exponent do not contribute, also exponent only helps in deciding the range. 
For example, an fractional field containing 10 bits would be able to represent log10(2^10) = 3 decimal places. 
Where as a field containing 40 bits would be able to represent 12 decimal places. 
For an example lets say the sign bit is positive, exponent represents 10^-10. 
Then the fractional number would be fraction * 2^-10.
If the fraction is 3 bits and 12 bits, the LSB change will have the following result:
3 bits:
000 => (1 ) * 2^-10
001 => (1 + 2^-3) * 2^-10
change: 2^-13
12 bits:
000000000000 => (1 ) * 2^-10
000000000001 => (1 + 2^-12) * 2^-10
change: 2^-22

Thus , we observe more precison with more number of fractional bits.

Q2)

Normal and Subnormal values
A subnormal number is any number which is smaller than the smallest normally representable number. This is used for representing smaller numbers around the zero.
In a normal number a leading 1 is assumed in the fractional part. By assuming this leading 1, we are increasing our precision but the lower limit is set to be 1. 
In a sub normal number, the exponent is the lowest possible number, then the leading 1 is not assumed thereby allowing us to represent more smaller numbers around zero.
For example in a 3 bit system, sign = +, exponent = 000 => 2^-4

if fraction = 000 is considered normal with leading bit: number = 1 * 2^-4 is the smallest number possible. if fraction = 001 is considered subnormal without leading 
bit: number = 2^-6 is the smallest number possible.

Consider number line as below: (Numbers specifies mantissa)
Normal representation matissa is > |1| while in subnormal representation, mantissa is smaller number less than one

<----------------- -1 ------------0------------- 1 ---------------------------- 2 --------------  .....   ------>
<----- -ve Normal -><---- Subnormal -------------><---------- +ve Normal -----------------------  .....   ------>

So, subnormal numbers are used to represent small numbers around zero, with loss in precision. 

Q3)
IEEE 754vv Standards of Floating Point Number Rounding are :

(a) Round to nearest even number: rounds to the nearest value with an even least significant digit. 

(b) Round to nearest, away from zero: rounds to the nearest value away from zero.

(c) Rounded toward zero: Rounds towards the value towards zero 

(d) Rounded toward infinity: Rounds towards the value towards infinity 

(e) Rounded toward -infinity: Rounds towards the value towards -infinity 

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Values ---->			3.20  	      3.60 	  3.50 	      6.50 	   –2.50     -3.50
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
▪ Towards zero 			 3		3 	    3 		6 	    –2          -3
▪ Round down (−∞) 		 3 		3	    3		6	    –3		-4	
▪ Round up (+∞) 		 4 		4 	    4 		7	    –2		-4
▪ Nearest Even          	 4 		4 	    4 		6 	    –2		-4
▪ Nearest away from zero	 4 		4           4 		7 	    –2		-3			